A Guide to the Edward H. Peeples, Jr. Papers, n.d., 1915, 1920s-2005
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
- Broad Subject Areas n.d., 1950s-2000 (Box 8-18)
  - School Inequality, 1960s (Box 15)
    - Southern School News, Jan. 1964-Dec. 1964 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Southern School News, Jan. 1965-June 1965 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Violence Prevention, n.d., 1990-2000 (Box 16)
    - Annabella R. Jenkins Foundation Symposium, n.d., 1999 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Anti-crime rally fliers, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Article about violence, Peeples, and the Prevention Program, Richmond Times- Dispatch July 5, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Blacks Mobilizing Against Crime, Help Stop Crime Conference, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Capitol Forum, 1992 - 1993 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Cartoons (political and newspaper) on Firearms, n.d., 1980s, 1990s (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Commonwealth of Virginia Commission on Family Violence Prevention, 1994 - 1995 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Crime Summit, n.d., 1990 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Department of Criminal Justice Services, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Editorials - Violence (several copies), June 22, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Firearms - Editorial by Peeples, Richmond Times-Dispatch, Nov. 2, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Ginter Park Presbyterian Peace Forum, n.d., 1995 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Governor's Commission on Violent Crime, 1992 - 1993 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Homicide Study of Medical Examiner Charts, n.d., 1994 - 1996, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Interact, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Leadership Metro Richmond, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - "A Look at the Culture of Violence in America and a Few Questions for Our World Neighbors Who Want to be More Like Us" by Peeples, 1996 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Medical College of Virginia (MCV) Current Concepts in Trauma Care, n.d., 1994 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Mental Health Association of Virginia - Violence in Our Communities, n.d., 1994 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Metro Violence Prevention Consortium, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d., 1983, 1992, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1990, 1992 - 1994 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings, 1990 - 1991, 1993 - 1995, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous presentation notes, n.d., 1992-1994 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Miscellaneous Virginia Commonwealth University (VCU) publications, n.d., 1990, 1994, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Networking, Inc. - Violence in the Community: Issues, Solutions and An Opportunistic Sampling of Family Violence Programs and Problems Across Virginia: A Preliminary Needs Assessment, 1993-1994 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Primary Care Noon Conference - The Effect of Violence on Children, n.d., 1996 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Regional Crime Commission - Recommendations, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Responsibilities, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Richmond Violence Prevention Forum - In Pursuit of Peace, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - Richmond Violence Prevention Forum - Sharing Solutions, n.d., 1990 (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Second Campus Sexual Assault Conference, 1993, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - "Seeds of Violence" - Special edition of Richmond Times-Dispatch, Oct. 9, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - Sexual Assault Prevention in Virginia Report, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - State Board of Health, n.d., 1994 (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - University of Richmond - Community Problem Solving Seminar, n.d., 1995 (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - Virginia Council on Social Welfare, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 37)
    - Virginia Department for the Prevention of Youth Violence, n.d., 1993 (Box 16, Folder 38)
    - Virginia Department of Health, n.d., 1994-1995 (Box 16, Folder 39)
    - Virginia Historical Society - Violence, Social Work, and Health Care, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 40)
    - Virginia Institute of Political Leadership Forum - Political, Social Demographics, and Public Policy Issues, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 41)
    - Virginia Public Health Association, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 42)
    - Virginia Public Health Association (VPHA) and Southern Health Association (SHA) Annual Meeting - Violence Prevention: A Community Responsibility, n.d., 1995 (Box 16, Folder 43)
    - "Weapon Carrying Fighting and Suicidality Among Students in Virginia's Public Schools" by John P. Slatterly, [report to governor of Virginia] c.1993, and newspaper clippings, 1994, c. 1993, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 44)
  - VCU Violence Prevention Project, n.d., 1992-1995 (Box 17-18)
    - Annual Report, 4th Quarter, 1992 - 1993 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Annual Report, 4th Quarter, (copy 1) 1993 - 1994 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Annual Report, 4th Quarter, (copy 2) 1993 - 1994 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Annual and Final Report, (folder 1 of 4) 1994 - 1995 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Annual and Final Report, (folder 2 of 4) 1994 - 1995 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Annual and Final Report, (folder 3 of 4) 1994 - 1995 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Annual and Final Report, (folder 4 of 4) 1994 - 1995 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Article on Violence from Journal of American Medical Association, Vol. 267, no. 22, June 10, 1992 1992 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - The Atlanta Project, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Brochures, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - "Building Safe Communities" National Center for Education in Maternal and Child Health, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Children and Violence; gun violence, brochures and pamphlets, n.d., 1989-1995 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - "City of Richmond, Urban Violence Strategy," draft and correspondence, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Community Coalition to Prevent Black Homicide, n.d., 1981 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Consortium, Agendas, Correspondence, n.d., 1992-1993 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Contact List for Metro Richmond Violence Prevention Consortium, January 1993, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - "Coordination and Cooperation Improve Program in Violence Prevention" Capitol Forum, February 1993 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 1968, 1991-1994 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, n.d., 1992-1995 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence and brochures from Injury Prevention Centers, n.d., 1991 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence and ephemera from Operation Peace in Philadelphia, n.d., 1993-1995 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Directory of Violence Prevention Resources, Richmond, 1990 - 1993 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Emergency Medical Service Workers and Violence, reports, brochures, and flyers n.d. (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Goldstein, Arnold, reports and articles n.d. (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Governor's Commission on Violent Crime, Virginia Budget, Town Meeting Flyers, FDA Officer on Consumer Affairs, Association of State and Territorial Health (ASTHO), Conference on Women's Health, 1992-1993 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Handouts and Slides Volume I - Program Materials, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Handouts and Slides Volume II - Data A 1994 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Handouts and Slides Volume III - Data B 1994 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Handouts and Slides Volume IV - Firearms 1994 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Handouts and Slides Volume V - Data / Ideas from Others, Leading Indicators, Lists, Bibliography 1994 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Handouts and Slides Volume VI - Virginia State Police Reports 1994 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Handouts, data, prevention materials, 1990 - 1993 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Handout List, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - History and correspondence, 1989-1995 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - "Hospital Protocol for Child Abuse," Virginia Department of Social Services, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Illinois Council for the Prevention of Violence (ICPV) newsletters, report, n.d., 1993 - 1994 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - "In Inventory of Risk Factors, Causes, and Predictor Variables for Violent Events and Intentional Injuries," by Peeples, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Jackson State University - An Urban Violence Conference, n.d. 1995 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - "Leading Indicators of Violence", 1993 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - "A List of Optimum Data Elements", 1995 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Materials from presentation, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Newspaper articles, 1989, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Objectives for Urban Violence Strategy, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - "Products, Program Proposals, and Services", (folder 1 of 2) 1994 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - "Products, Program Proposals, and Services", (folder 2 of 2) 1994 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - "A Proposal for an Injury Prevention, Treatment, and Research Center" by Peeples, proposal and correspondence, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Race riots, newspaper clippings, reports, and newsletter, 1967-1971 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Regional Crime Commission Final Report, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - "Report and Proposal - Surveillance and Prevention of Violent Acts", 1990-1991 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - "Reported Experience with Violence in an Opportunistic Sample Collected by The Richmond City Health Department", by Peeples, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Richmond Academy of Medicine - The 1995 Public Health Seminar on Urban and Domestic Violence "Report and Proposal - Surveillance and Prevention of Violent Acts", 1990 - 1991 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Substance Abuse, Family Violence, Criminal Justice brochures, 1991 - 1995, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - "Together against Violence" Statewide Public Awareness Campaign Against Violence, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Ukrop, James, correspondence and speech, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - "Update: Violent Event Analysis Team" 1994 (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - Violence and Adolescents, report, articles, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - Violence and Youth, articles, brochures, newsletters, 1982-1997 (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - "Violent Crime Task Force Report: A Report of the Metropolitan Richmond Chamber of Commerce", 1989 (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - "Violence Facts on File 1990" 1990 (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - Violence Incidence Screening Instrument and Survey, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - Violence Prevention and Treatment Resources, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 36)
    - Violence Prevention Update, newsletters, n.d., 1992-1993 (Box 18, Folder 37)
    - Virginia State Police records, n.d., 1990-1994 (Box 18, Folder 38)
    - William Byrd Community House, n.d., 1993-1995 (Box 18, Folder 39)
- Miscellaneous Topics n.d., 1920s, 1950s-2001 (Box 19-21)
  - AIDS Medical Advisory Committee, n.d., 1985-1993 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Activ 5 Theatre Project, 1996 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - American Friends Services Committee, Memos, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Appalachia - Modernization of Life Styles," Unit 7, by Lewis Donahew and B. Krishna Singh, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Appalachia - "The Knox Co. Community Action Program of the Office of Economic Opportunity", 1967 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - The Carolina Israelite, 1958, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Coalition for a Safer Richmond, Ernie Brown, n.d., 1994, 1997-1998 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - "The Collected Sayings of Chairman Henry" (Henry Howell), pamphlet, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Community Learning Week Roundtable - includes news clippings, text of remarks by Peeples, Souvenirs, Jan 1984 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Curacao - History of the island materials, n.d., ca. 1999 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Curacao - Itinerary, news clippings, flyers, brochures, stamps, coins n.d., 1999-2000 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Curacao - maps, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Curacao - Miscellaneous museum materials, and Colors, journal of Curacao [museum video is in Box 26] n.d., 1998 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Curacao - Museum materials ca. 2000 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - David E. Satterfield, 3d: Democratic Representative from Virginia, Ralph Nader Project, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Eastern Kentucky Syndrome - articles, correspondence, notes, 1967, 1970s (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Elevators and Smoking, n.d., 1979, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Folk Medicine - articles, newspaper clippings and miscellaneous, 1960s-1980s (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Folk Medicine - scholarly articles, 1950s-1970s (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Fortune News from the fortune Society (prisoner's rights), 1975-1976 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Hollow-Point Ammunition (dumdum bullets), Statements to Richmond City Council (one by Peeples), brochure, newspaper clippings, 1974-1975 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Homosexuality - Articles, data, newspaper clippings, 1969-1975 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Human Rights Day Dinner, Richmond Human Rights Coalition, 1979-1991 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Kepone and other environmental hazards, n.d., 1978-1992 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - "The Last Days of the Pen" Richmond Times Dispatch newspaper article, June 29, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - "Maintaining an Union-Free Health Care Agency" [MCV Conference cancelled by Governor Charles Robb), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - METRO Richmond Coalition Against Drugs, 1994-1995 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Metro Teen Program, YMCA, VCU, Richmond, Virginia, 1998-1999 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Newspaper clippings, miscellaneous topics, 1969, 1970s, 1980s (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Our Own Community Press (Gay and Lesbian community) - newspaper clippings, 1989-1990 (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Pet food consumption by humans - Correspondence, articles, newspaper clippings, 1974-1975 [1 0f 3] (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Pet food consumption by humans - Correspondence, articles, newspaper clippings, 1974-1975 [2 of 3] (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Pet food consumption by humans - Correspondence, articles, newspaper clippings, 1974-1975 [3 of 3] (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Pet food consumption by humans - Hartley W. Barclay (Executive Director, Management Research Institute), photograph, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Photographs of Margaret and Ken Morland by Peeples, c. 2000 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Prince Edward County - VCU web site using Peeples's materials, c. 2001 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Richmond Chapter of the ACLU, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Richmond Human Rights Coalition - news clippings, misc. publications, Coalition reports, includes "Origins of Richmond Human Rights Coalition" by Peeples, n.d., 1974-1993 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Richmond News Leader - Editorial, editorial cartoons, 1969-1990 Richmond politics and news - news clippings, 1980s (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Richmond politics and news - news clippings, 1980s (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Richmond RESULTS (anti-hunger, anti-poverty organization), n.d., 1990s (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Richmond Times Dispatch, c. 1920s, 1923, 1933 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Richmond Times Dispatch - Editorials, 1985-1989 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Richmond Times Dispatch - Editorials, 1980-1985 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Richmond Times Dispatch - miscellaneous clippings, 1970, 1971, 1975, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Richmond Times Dispatch - misc. clippings, 1964-1969 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Richmond Times Dispatch - WWII, news clippings, 1943-1944 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Richmond Urban Institute, 1980s (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Second hand smoke, articles and correspondence, 1974, 1976, 1979, 1986, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Southside Unity Center (Blackwell neighborhood, Southside Richmond), n.d., 1990-1996 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Sterilization in Virginia, news clippings, 1980s (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Subversive Organizations List, 1955; Correspondence from U.S. Dept. of Justice, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Thalhimer's card belonging to Peeples, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - United Nations Bill of Human Rights and Universal Declaration of Human Rights, pamphlets, 1976-1980 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Virginid Department of Health - Sexual Assault Services Program Committee, n.d., 1996-1999 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Virginia Electric and Power Company (VEPCO) - The Committee for Responsible Government, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Virginia Human Rights Act - Proposed Legislation, 1981-1987 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Virginia State Penitentiary - Family Life Program, ACLU Report, news clippings on prison, n.d., 1970s-1980s (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Virginia State Penitentiary - (inmate at Virginia State Penn.) - Family Life Program, State Penn, n.d., 1987-1989 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Virginia State Penitentiary - (inmate at Virginia State Penn.), 1978-1980 (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - White House Conference on Food, Nutrition and Health - correspondence and news clippings, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Women's Issues - article, news clipping, 1971, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - Your Schools - South Carolina Community Relations Program American Friends Service Committee, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - "Youth, Justice and Social Change" seminar attended by Peeples and international students in Rodica, Yugoslavia, July 15-30, 1968 - includes postcards from Yugoslavia, list of attendees, and photographs of participants, including Peeples 1968 (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Allen, Theodore William, Article and Program for Memorial Service, October 8, 2005 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Arey, Calvin- Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Bradley, Bill (Senator, New Jersey) - Violence in America, National Press Club, 1984 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Byrd, Harry F. (Jr. and Sr.) Time magazine article (1962), Newspaper articles, 1962, 1963-1985 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Capek, Peter- Czechoslovakia, 1969-1975 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Cheek, Mary Tyler, article in Style Weekly, Jan. 8, 1991 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Conrad, Rob- "The Oppression of Liberal News and Opinion by Richmond Newspapers," c. 1985 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Dabney, Virginius- Articles, editorials, 1964-1985 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Gregory, Edward Meeks, "Pope"- Correspondence, newspaper clippings, 1984-1995 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Guild, June Purcell- Articles and correspondence, 1936-1996 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Hill, Oliver - Invitation to the dedication of the Oliver Hill Courts Building (August 2, 1996), newspaper articles on Hill 1989-1999 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Hopkins, Evan Correspondence, newspaper clippings poetry, 1982-1995 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Johnson, Dr. R. Walter - Memorial tennis courts - Photos, 2003 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - LaRouche, Lyndon - The Campaigner, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - LaRouche, Lyndon - Executive Intelligence Review, 1984 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - LaRouche, Lyndon - Miscellaneous articles and publications, 1970s-1980s (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - LaRouche, Lyndon - National Caucus of Labor Committees, publications, 1972-1973 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - LaRouche, Lyndon - National Caucus of Labor Committees - correspondence, newspaper clippings, notes and photographs regarding Peeples' study of Lyndon LaRouche's Labor Party, n.d., 1973-1974, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - LaRouche, Lyndon - National Caucus of Labor Committees - publications, 1972-1973 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - LaRouche, Lyndon - The Organizer, Oct. 14, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - LaRouche, Lyndon - New Solidarity, 1973-1984 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - LaRouche, Lyndon - Newspaper clippings, 1970s (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - LaRouche, Lyndon - Newspaper clippings, 1980s (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - LaRouche, Lyndon - Newspaper clippings, 1990s (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - LaRouche, Lyndon - Newspaper clippings, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - LaRouche, Lyndon - Photos of supporters (two) at Batltimore airport, June 1987 (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - U.S. Labor Party and National Unemployed and Labor Rights Organization (NU-WRD), Richmond, Virginia, c. 1974 (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - Lee, Rev. Heslip "Happy" - article and invitation, 2003, 2004 (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Robbins, Tom Correspondence, newspaper clippings, short story, 1961/1962, 1980s, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Robinson, Spottwood Program from memorial service, newspaper clippings, 1998 (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Scacco, Anthony Correspondence, newspaper clippings, 1977-1984 (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - Svitak, Ivan Youth, Justice, and Social Change, Correspondence, 1968-1993 (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Wilder, Doug Correspondence, photographs, invitation, c. 1989-1990 (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - Wilder, Doug Newspaper clippings, 1989-1990 (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - Willis, Kent [Virginia ACLU] Caricatures, correspondence, photo, resume 1980s (Box 21, Folder 35)
- Miscellaneous audio and visual materials (slides, audio and video recordings, phonographs, photographs), publications, ephemera, and oversize materials. 1930s-2004 (Box 22-36)
  - Slides for Peeples' class lectures - each slide has a number given to it by Peeples that corresponds with an index card with information about the slide. Subjects include "Defining Disease," "MCV Cancer Rehab. Program/Evaluation," "Stress Impact Study/Methodology," "Health Behavior," and "Violence Prevention." c. 1970s-1980s (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Slides for Peeples' class lectures - each slide has a number given to it by Peeples that corresponds with an index card with information about the slide. Subjects include "Defining Disease," "MCV Cancer Rehab. Program/Evaluation," "Stress Impact Study/Methodology," "Health Behavior," and "Violence Prevention." c. 1970s-1980s (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Song Book - Sing Kentucky (traditional songs), 96 pp paper n.d. (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Song Book - Bound for Glory - 101 Woody Guthrie Songs, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Sheet Music - We Shall Overcome and Lift Every Voice and Sing, c. early 1960s (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Sheet Music - Somewhere, We Shall Not Be Moved, and I'm On My Way to Freedom Land (1 page song sheet), c. early 1960s (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Sheet Music - Blowin' in the Wind (1 page song sheet), c. early 1960s (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Sheet Music - We Shall Overcome, The Hammer Song, and This Land is Your Land, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Working Class - 45 RPM Record - "A Working Man Can't Get Nowhere Today," Merle Haggard, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Working Class - 45 RPM Record - "Take This Job and Shove It"; "Colorado Kool-Aid," Johnny Paycheck, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Working Class - 45 RPM Record - "Redneck Roots," Vernan Oxford, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Working Class - 45 RPM Record - "I'm Just a Redneck in a Rock and Roll Bar," Jerry Reed, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Working Class - 45 RPM Record - "Y'All Come Back Saloon," Oak Ridge Boys, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - White Supremacy - 45 RPM Record - "We Don't Want Niggers in Our Schools," side 1; "Nigger, Nigger," side 2, by The Coon Hunters, Reb-Time Records, Oldways Pub. Co., circa 1968 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - White Supremacy - 45 RPM Record - "We Is Non-Violent Niggers," side 1; "Ship Those Niggers Back," side 2, by Odis Cochran and Guitar with the 3 Bigots, Hatenanny Records, Box 5505, Arlington Virginia, G.L. Rockwell Party Inc. n.d. (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Songs For a Better Tomorrow, International Union, UAW, [phonograph, 33 RPM], 1963 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Sing Out! Hootenanny with Pete Seeger and the Hooteneers, Folkways Records, [phonograph, 33 RPM], 1963 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Cleveland Francis - Follow Me, [phonograph, 33 RPM], n.d. (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Flatt and Scruggs with Doc Watson, Stricktly Instrumental, [phonograph, 33 RPM], n.d. (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Peter Seeger and Frank Hamilton, Nonsuch and Other Folk Tunes, Folkways Records, [phonograph, 33 RPM], 1959 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Hylo Brown, Bill Clifton and his Dixie Mountain Boys, and others, Spectacular Bluegrass Favorites with 5 String Banjo, Palace, [phonograph, 33 RPM], circa early 1960s (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Jack Guy and Tab Ward, The Beech Mountain Ramblers, Walking in the Parlor, Beech Creek Records, purchased in Beech Creek, North Carolina, [phonograph, 33 RPM], n.d. (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Bill and Jean Davis, Old Traditions, dulcimer and guitar, [phonograph, 33 RPM], 1967 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - George Winn and Red Battle and the Bluegrass Partners, Blues Plus Bluegrass - Part Two, Major Recording Co., Waynesboro, [phonograph, 33 RPM], circa 1960s (Box 24, Folder 22)